# Ajay Singh

Admin & Security Officer

experience in security, maintaining training records, log books, office correspondence, office inventory and HR Management. Able to handle multiple weapons like revolver, INSAS and LMG. During 20 years of service in Indian Air Force, served in many Air Force Installations, both under peace and highly operational conditions. Physically and mentally fit air warrior who participated in various games during defence career. Presently serving as Admin & Security officer at Indian Security Service, Gurugram. Competent to take quickest action with least trouble and greater



ajayasmit0501@gmail.com



8375923021



Gurugram, Haryana, India

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Trainee**

Airmen Training School

06/2001 - 03/2004

AC(U/T)

· Completed basic and trade training during the mentioned period. Self defence techniques and hard core physical training was provided by expert team of ground training instructors. Learned different types of weapon handling like revolver, INSAS

#### **Operations Assistant**

Transportable Radar Unit

03/2004 - 12/2006

Air Craftsman

• Four years of experience in Transportable Radar Unit which includes area reconnaissance, troops movement and air defence operations.

#### Office Assistant

Air Defence College

12/2006 - 04/2011

LAC / Corporal

• Five years experience at Air Defence College as supporting staff for training activities of Fighter Controllers. Completed basic computer courses and worked in training wing to look after as NCO ic of various reputed courses.

#### **In-Charge Section**

Glaciers

04/2011 - 05/2013

Corporal

Corporal

• Served in glaciers for two years. Looked after air maintenance operations, Fund management iro annual training grant and aerospace safety funds. Participated in various joint operations with Indian Army at glaciers.

#### Office Supervisor

Map Digitisation Centre

05/2013 - 09/2017

Sergeant

 Five years experience in creating various formats of digital maps. Performed duties as incharge of quick response team (QRT). Worked as office supervisor and looked after office correspondence & purchases.

# **Senior Non Commissioned Officer ic Operations**

Aerostat Radar

09/2017 - 06/2021

## **SKILLS**

## COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

Computer Fundamentals (02/2011 - 03/2011)

UPTEC

Office Automation and Internet (11/2009 - 12/2009)

Mahendra:s

Digitisation of Cartographic Documents (09/2015 - 10/2015)

• Indian Institute of Surveying and Mapping

Adobe in Design (01/2017 - 01/2017)

National Institute of Information Technology

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts with Office Management, Secretarial Practice as subjects (60.10%) IGNOU, New Delhi, India

Master of Arts - Rural Development (62.13%) IGNOU, New Delhi, India

Master of Arts - Hindi Literature (69.27%) IGNOU. New Delhi. India

# **LANGUAGES**

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency